[Music]
how exciting is this we are going to be
studying The Book of Revelation I know
this is the culmination of months maybe
even over a year H you Von I think so of
Daring to dream yes come on now come on
come dream we talked about this actually
originally uh before all of us ended up
sitting here together we talked about
this with a man by the name of Will
pergerson and Will was a personal friend
friend of mine and of Christ's he had a
vision a dream he was an evangelist a
powerful speaker a man of God and he had
a vision and a dream for the Book of
Revelation and explaining the Book of
Revelation with a very strong emphasis
on Christ and I believe that uh will
would have been here with us of course I
know he would have been with us here
today this is what he wanted but tragic
accident took his life last year and we
want to dedicate this first program to
well yeah to his glory and we know he's
resting in Christ and we know that uh
he's going to hear the voice of Christ
and that trumpet call in the morning and
he's going to be there he we will not
precede him it says in first
Thessalonians chapter 4 well this
program is going to be pretty basic
pretty simple we're going to be opening
up the Book of Revelation we're going to
be looking through the pages the verses
and trying to understand it now I come
from a background of studying this book
for some 30 years and yet not really
understanding it fully still and I
believe that's because the book is a
masterpiece it's it's it's a challenging
book and I think we're going to be
studying through all eternity it's a
summary of the entire Bible in a way but
it is a book that's filled with symbolic
language it's a book that's filled with
mysterious
representations of events and history
past present and future it's a book that
is difficult to understand a book that's
been blessed because God wants to
encourage us to to study it and to
understand it so I'm here at the table
with that background I want to know a
little bit about your backgrounds and
your relationship to but Jason let's
start with you well I'm relatively new
to the church uh coming back and
Revelation is a book that's full of
symbols and signs and it's it's
confusing to me so I mean there's a lot
of um it's kind of like a treasure map
so you're trying to figure out you know
what times what
kingdom does this symbol represent what
are these Seven Stars what are the seven
K what are what are all these things so
I'm I'm looking forward to learning um
about Revelation super love it love it
yeah
I'm I guess I have read Revelation more
than one time and I still don't have the
kind of grasp on it that I want I I feel
like um even though I've read it even
though I've read commentary on it I
still don't have that feeling of you
know that I really kind of know know it
and and I guess you know to kind of uh
reinforce what you were saying I guess
you never fully know it but I could have
a better grasp on it so I I think that
there are a lot of people who you know
who have read through it like like I
have but they just kind of I still don't
really know so I'm looking forward to
this study because I really feel like
this is going to open it up in a whole
new way amen praise the Lord deal
especially with the holy spirit being
amen good deal so my introduction to the
Book of Revelation came when I was
uh 12 years old 12 years old and I was
not a Christian okay I had a cousin that
had um come over from England and
she began to talk to me about the mark
of the
beast at 12 years
old I had seen this movie about this
little boy MH who discovers he's the
Antichrist and anyone who finds out his
um his
identity dies a mysterious death
mhm so she's there telling me hey I know
what the mark of the beast is do you
want to know what the mark of the beast
is and I'm like oh oh my
goodness if I know what if I know what
the mark of the beast is I'm going to
die oh you were taking that movie
seriously
huh she told me it was a there were soap
companies that produced or soap
companies that had uh a label on their
boxes half circle oh a half a circle
with a half moon and a man's face in
it uh she showed me the box I ran out
the house screaming
oh I am about to
die that was my introduction to the book
of of
Revelation but uh and and that kind of
put a taste in my after I didn't die I
was like okay man I think I want to know
more about this
book and so um it was years later as a
as a actually as a young adult I
probably like 21 or 22 that um I was
introduced to the book in a way that I
had I I grown up really really skeptic
of the Bible mhm and um uh someone
introduced the book to me I didn't know
his background but he was a well learned
young man in the Book of Revelation and
he began to like break things down in a
way that
um really caused me to walk away from a
contract I was in a music uh music
career and it was so powerful so amazing
that I actually walked away from this
contract um to look back so the Book of
Revelation has become a you know one of
the books that for me is the most
exciting book of the Bible it just um
and I know there's a lot of fear with
people when they when they come to that
book like I was when I was 12 you know I
don't want to know this stuff because
there's dragons and you know things are
going to come up out of the ocean I
don't want to be here when that
happens um but understanding that these
things represent symbols and and signs
um of of Greater realities and that
there's not going to be like literal
locusts uh that look like you know men
and you know those kind of things once I
got that understanding the book became
um my favorite book of the
Bible mine too yeah mine too I can
totally relate to that and that's why I
think this is going to be exciting
because okay you have that interest in
the Book of Revelation you love The Book
of Revelation I have that same interest
in the desire um Jason is a novice when
it comes to the Book of Revelation he's
he's acknowledging hey I really don't
get this book I mean it's full of signs
and symbols but I don't get it and yavon
has read it a few times and you've got a
grasp on it but yeah I'd like to know a
little bit better and I think you guys
are going to help moderate us and
together we're going to be able to move
through this book in a way that should
open up more and more understanding
because I believe the Holy Spirit wants
to teach all of God's people and when we
get together even more so the Holy
Spirit wants to teach you you you and me
and now four times as much because all
four of us are together yeah and and I
believe that this book is a book for the
end of time specifically and especially
now we're going to look at the book
we're going to break it down uh just as
an overview just to kind of to to make
it into more bite-sized pieces sometimes
when you when you come into the Book of
Revelation like where do I start you
know and how do I get even a grip on
this well we're going to break it down
into four basic sections with an
introduction and a close the
introduction is going to be Revelation 1
that's the introduction to the book yeah
and I'm going to add to that that um I
think one of the things that people uh
look at when they get to the Book of
Revelation is that they think it's a
book that's really
just uh out of order uh that there's no
rhythm or rhyme to it but when you
understand that the Book of Revelation
is I like to call it divinely designed
that's when you begin to see oh there is
meaning to this and you can't just fit
anything in there it has to follow the
pattern okay so when I was um 19 I had
an I had an experience that I never
forgot and I share this all the time I
don't know if you ever seen those
pictures that uh are just like zigzag
lines and well let me tell you about I'm
in the mall with my friends and we're I
see all these people around this picture
and they're going oh look at that look
at so they C my interest I went over
there and it's just zigzag lines and I'm
looking at these people like you are
crazy you see and then someone said no
no you have to do this thing with your
eyes and I was like do what and they
were like you got to focus on a
particular so I'm trying to do all these
things with my eyes you
know and then suddenly I don't know if I
focused it on one point or what happened
but that picture that was just zigzag
zigzag line suddenly became 3D when I
moved the picture moved and now I was
like what you
serious so to many people The Book of
Revelation yeah oh they just zigzag
lines oh I love it good I can't see
anything I mean where's it what are you
getting so excited about James you know
what are you getting but when you see
that there's a pattern to the book and
that's what we'll be talking about in
these you know in this opening lesson
when there's a when you see the pattern
to the book you see that there is one
behind that pattern a Divine designer
and that pattern really helps to make
Things Come Alive come alive and like 3D
for us if you will good amen so we'll be
covering those patterns and hopefully
that will bring it to life yes I love
that you know and again I I reminds me
of when I was first studying The Book of
Revelation and I decided to rewrite it
in order I wanted to put all the second
comings in order and I wanted to put all
the judgments in order and I wanted to
put everything about Christ in so that
because it wasn't written in order I
don't know who put this
together don't know who inspired this
book and put it in this order but you
know it needed to be and since then I've
realized you know the more I've studied
the Book of Revelation The more I've
realized how little I know about the
book so I don't think any of us should
should be uh handicapped by the idea
that hey we're just not scholarly this
book is just too much for us this is too
difficult it's kind of like Iver when he
first looked at that pain he's like I'm
not getting anything out of this man
everyone else is but I'm not sometimes
we come to the Book of Revelation that
way and we don't need to to to feel as
though we're on the outside oh that guy
knows all about Revelation I'll just sit
at his feet I'll just learn what he no
God wants to actually communicate to us
all of us and show us what this book
means good now one of the keys I think
to understanding The Book of Revelation
is to break it down into these sections
and to allow Christ to be the center
that is something that I know was on
will Perkinson heart Pastor Perkinson 's
heart and I know it's on IV's heart it's
on my heart when we look at the Book of
Revelation sometimes we do think about
these gloomy pictures we think about
negative things Martin Luther wrote uh
an introduction to the Book of
Revelation in the year
1522 and in that introduction he said uh
Book of Revelation doesn't really belong
to the Canon it shouldn't really be part
of the Bible um Christ isn't there you
know he's not known in there he's not
taught in there um but you know it was
part so he wrote this introduction
talked about the Book of Revelation 8
years later Martin Luther changed his
opinion 8 years later in his in his
editing of the introduction of
Revelation he said we see now that
Christ is both taught and center of the
Book of
Revelation and that was I think a
breaking point for Luther that really
was where his mind now was able to grasp
the Prophecies of Revelation because in
a nutshell just in a nutshell what
Revelation is doing it's introducing us
to Christ and the god gospel and then
introducing us to that power that
influence that is symbolized by a dragon
that is going to counterfeit Christ and
the gospel that's that it that's it in a
nutshell it's Christ and the gospel
here's the gospel here's Christ here's
how it all works now be aware of this
Dragon because he's actually come down
and he's trying to take from you what
Christ has giving to you and he's trying
to counterfeit everything that Christ
has established and we're going to see
that all through Revelation we're going
to see the truth counterfeit the truth
counterfeit the truth counterfeit oh
that's great in all the symbols I would
say the best way um to um understand
really any subject of the Bible is you
know how can I juice this down if you
will to a level that you know I could
explain it in a minute you know so just
like what we just heard okay really it's
about Christ and the dragon and them
Waring over the people of God or over
Humanity you know the uh the more ways
you can sum it up for your own self the
better you you begin to feel more
comfortable approaching the book because
now you're going to be trying to trace
that theme yes right right okay so
Christ Dragon people where do I find
that in Revelation one Revelation 2
Revelation three going all the way
through so the more you can you can um
you can find these these patterns these
parallels these uh themes M and then uh
you you now have something you can
trace you know through the whole book it
instead of just jumping in and all right
I'm reading Revelation 11 where does
this fit what is it about you know
without the a theme or without the
context right yeah it's zigzag lines
well let's look at that Jason would you
read for us Revelation 1 verse 5 sure
and we'll just pick this out here in
this verse and from Jesus Christ who is
the faithful witness and the first
begotten of the dead and the Prince of
kings of the kings of the trth of uh
excuse me of the kings of the earth unto
him that loved us and washed us from our
sins in his own blood now what ia was
just saying applies to this verse what
we have here is we have a picture of
Christ and we have a picture of Satan
and we have a picture of us okay the
picture of Christ is a picture of love
and by the way it's really interesting
uh a few years ago there was a CNN blog
uh they have a religious blog on CNN
and in this blog it was March of 2012
they had interviewed basically
a a scholar a Biblical scholar and asked
them about the Book of Revelation and
this biblical scholar said basically the
Book of Revelation was forced into the
Canon kind of like what Martin Luther
came up with it was forced into the
cannon it doesn't really belong there we
don't even know if John was the author
and we don't know if the author read
even the gospels and there's nowhere in
the Book of Revelation that even says
that Jesus died for our sins h and the
thing that got me about that uh is that
really brought home to me is because
because really Revelation 1 verse 5 the
verse that you just read Jason tells us
that Jesus Christ died for us loves us
and washed us from our sins that's the
gospel right there okay so when this
scholar interviewed on CNN said this I
said wow so much for
scholarship so much for scholarship in
other words we don't need to depend on
the scholars when we open up the Book of
Revelation in fact it might be good not
to depend the scholars see that's a good
really good thing to think about
because you kind of ordinarily think
I've got to have somebody break it down
for me you know and and we're kind of
doing that here but yet we're asking the
Holy Spirit to to guide us and so in our
private study too we can ask the holy
spirit to guide us but this does I never
noticed this before this verse has the
gospel it's it's John 3:16 I I love the
idea of finding Christ
MH in this book in every nook and cranny
that we can because it it gives it a new
meaning now we're not just focusing on
the dark side right right but now we're
focusing on the love of Jesus and what
he did and how he's going to protect us
in the end and all of that so to me
that's that's that's awesome to find
Jesus in every in every nook andc think
that is definitely important um what you
guys are saying about learning it you
have to learn it for yourself um because
somebody else might get it get it wrong
and they're teaching you wrong you need
to learn for yourself what truth is amen
absolutely no and I'm going to share
this that the the the fact that the
Bible I believe is divinely
designed is a way of actually checking
your conclusions mhm because just like a
math problem you know you do a math
problem then you reverse the problem to
see if you got it right the Bible
especially the Book of Revelation has
those
builtin mechanisms where you can see am
I right on this or am I wrong you know
because as you it it's got to fit in the
pattern okay if you understand the big
picture the pattern you know well I
can't fit this in there because that
just throw throws off the entire pattern
the entire design and so all those
things com into play but what he's
saying about this um you know the the
gospel being in Revelation
1:5 is is a beautiful thought you know
the first chapter you have the
gospel and we should be looking for that
theme all the way through straight
through because because an introduction
to any good
book introduces the theme of the book
right so what is the theme of the book
well Revelation 1:1 it's the revelation
of Jesus Christ who loved us and washed
us from our sins in his blood and here's
the conflict you were talking about the
conflict we were talking about the
summary of the book you have Jesus and
you have the devil and you have us
where's the devil in this in this verse
who washed us from our sins where did
Sin come from well sin came from the
devil sin came from that adversary who
tempted Adam and Eve who began the whole
process of if you will rebellion in the
universe which by the way is in a sense
the this the Zenith of the Book of
Revelation 12 it gives us a picture of
this whole controversy and how it
started in heaven so Revelation 15 also
introduces in a sense to that dark side
to sin and guilt and shame and the the
thing that led us to hide from God and
be afraid of God and Jesus wants us to
know right away the first thing he wants
us to know right away in Revelation
first message of Revelation it's not
about a beast it's not about an
antichrist it's not about a dragon first
thing he wants us to know I love you and
I've washed you I've taken care of the
guilt I've taken care of the sin I've
taken care of the very thing that was
brought upon you by venturing into that
good and evil that knowledge I didn't
want you to have and listening to the
accusations the
insinuations uh of the the dragon which
was the serpent which is the devil I've
cleansed you from that I've washed you
from that I accept you I believe in you
you are mine and this is the the picture
we're having here that is I think is so
significant and beautiful yeah I want to
I'm going to take you on a on a very
quick just overview of that very theme
in the Book of
Revelation and uh it was interesting CU
as James and I were talking and and
sharing some of these some of our
different thoughts before our program
and we're just like we've never really
studied the Book of Revelation together
but we were amazed at how much we were
like who yeah yeah you're on the same
page while we're seeing this you know in
the very same way um but uh one of the
things that that we were sharing is that
uh The Book of Revelation and this how
I'd like to put it is actually a Love
Story love
it so when you put that for what
Revelation a love story no it's not it's
about beasts and Dragons but think about
it the Book of Revelation is about so
are love stories by the
way Prince rescues the woman from Dr
Absolut what do you have you have the
prince Jesus Christ you have his bride
the
church and you have this power saying
give me some time with your woman and I
bet you I can take her wow
that's basically what he's saying so the
entire Book of Revelation that theme of
Christ his bride and the dragon saying
I'm going to steal her from you you know
so now Revelation becomes a love story
and now just think of it when you think
of the Book of Revelation within that
context we know that in Revelation
chapter 1 you have John who is who Jesus
says John I want you to I'm calling you
to do something for me so John in
essence we can look at him as the friend
of the bridegroom okay then in chapters
2 and 3 you have the letters to the
seven churches so what are those those
are Jesus's love letters Love Letters to
his bride okay in chapters four and five
you have Jesus standing before the
father but what is he doing there he's
standing there on behalf of his
bride right chapter six uh deals with
the uh seven uh with the seals okay here
you you you you see the story of how
Satan is trying to corrupt the bride
trying to lead her away from her love
Revelation chapter 7 you have the
ceiling of the people of God so what is
that ceiling it's really the perfecting
of gods of Jesus's bride okay Revelation
8 through1 are the trumpets what is
Jesus doing there in the trumpets he is
protecting his bride throughout the ages
right from the time of the Cross which
we'll get into more detail but this is
just an overview M Revelation 12
to13 you have Satan physically
assaulting the bride going to make war
with the remnant of her seed I'm going
to persecute you and I'm going to
demonstrate that this woman doesn't love
you so I'm going to Institute something
called the mark of the beast and I bet
you that to save herself she'll receive
it wow those are the basic sections of
Revelation you've got the seven churches
the Seven Seals the seven trumpets and
then that last section which we call the
seven signs of salvation
those four Bas and all of those sections
repeat and enlarge they tell the same
story from a different angle it's very
similar to Daniel Daniel 278 and 11 are
four chapters that repeat and enlarge on
the same basic theme so you've got an
introduction in Revelation one and
you've got a close in revelation 22 and
then you've got these four basic themes
or stories that are told from different
angles covering the same ground and
giving more insight and more
understanding until we finally get to
this picture in Revelation 12 12 13 14
and onward that I think primarily
applies to us today and future to us in
other words that are that is just before
us and and James the story ends happily
ever after after oh see I never heard it
broken down like that before love Christ
comes to take his bride come to take his
bride home after he saves her saves the
day you know those plagues really the
plagues at the end of time are really
God saying you're not going to touch my
woman mhm wow how dare you try to put a
hand on her so the plagues are God are
Christ saying nope I'm protecting her he
comes to get the bride mhm goes home
with her to a wedding wow happily ever
after you you know wow that is so deep
um one author has said if a man is
really in love with a woman he'll do the
three PS he'll protect her he'll provide
for her and he'll profess her and Jesus
Does oh that's I like that that that
wraps up the picture really well I like
that so so when we're looking at the
Book of Revelation IV you going say
something no no no no no let's go into
the into the um sections yeah when we're
looking at the Book of Revelation we're
going to be looking at these these four
sections Revelation chapter 1 is what we
call the introduction of the prologue
Revelation chapters 2 and 3 seven
churches Revelation chapters 4 through
81 7even seals revelation CH 8: 2 to
1119 seven trumpets and then Revelation
12 all the way to 22 and verse 5 is what
we call the seven salvation signs and
we'll talk a little bit about what we
mean by that and then Revelation chap
226 um all the way through 2221 that's
going to be the epilog or the close
that's going to be the basic layout of
the Book of Revelation that we're going
to be looking at as we move through it
step by step and in our next program we
just got a couple minutes left here time
has flown by but in our next program
we're going to do an introduction and
we're just going to spend as much time
as as we need in Revelation chapter 1
we've we've kind of touched on it a
little bit but we're going to we're
going to start in Revelation chapter 1
now our goal for this series this first
series uh on Bible prophecy our goal is
to make it halfway through the book I
and I talked about it we sat down we we
over the phone and we went through a
number of different uh sessions together
outlines and we thought how far can we
get in the first session can we cover
the whole book no we can't cover there's
nowhere we're going to what about
halfway through yeah let's make that a
goal so our goal is to get through
Revelation 11 to to make it to
Revelation 12:1 however we are not
cemented into that goal we don't have to
get there that's good we're just going
to move through if we only get to
chapter two in the whole 13 sessions
that's fine if we get further than that
that's fine too what we'd like to do is
we would like to make sure that you guys
yavon Jason that you are moderating us
we want to be able to move through this
book no faster than you guys can
comprehend it and we want to be able to
understand and explain it in a sense
that anyone that is just listening in on
our conversation about this book is
going to get it it's going to click so
that's great what do you guys think is
that do you think that's a good plan I
think that's a good oh yeah I think
that's great I I like the idea of just
not being forced into a a time line you
know we just get it as we go as the
spirit moves we get it yeah cuz this is
heavy stuff you this is heavy stuff it
is and yet looking at this the uh
illustrations that some of the
illustrations that Ivor brought out you
know the love story illustration and the
illustration of Christ standing for his
bride while you know the dragon looking
at these illustrations to me really is
going to help us to comprehend these
truths so I'm looking forward to the
adventure that we're going to have me
too s together praise God let's pray
together as we close yes Father just
want to thank you for this opportunity
for this program for all you're doing
and going to do and pray that you'll
continue to bless us guide us lead us as
we study the Book of Revelation we pray
in Jesus name amen amen
[Music]
amen